Xi Peng

4400 Vestal Parkway East Vestal, NY 13850, USA +1 (917) 803-7402 • xpeng@binghamton.edu https://sites.google.com/site/xipengcshomepage/

RESEARCH INTEREST

Deep Learning, Machine Learning, and Intelligent Data Analytics such as Vision/Language Understanding. Training deep models usually requires intensive human efforts such as tons of data annotations and specialized training skills. My research aims to answer the question: can we reduce the efforts to achieve more efficient machine intelligence? More specifically,

- Can we reduce the data efforts by learning data augmentation?
 - Learning to learn in multimodality understanding: [ECCV'18] [AAAI'18 review]
 - Competitive and competitive data augmentation: [CVPR'18] [TPAMI'18 review]
 - Adversarial image and video generation: [IJCAI'18] [ECCV'18]
- Can we improve the network performance by leveraging domain knowledge?
 - Learning disentangled representations: [ECCV'16 oral] [ICCV'17] [IJCV'17]
 - Learning factorization and forecasting: [IJCV'18] [TVCG'18 review] [BMVC'18]
 - Attribute editing and retargeting: [CVIU'15] [BMVC'16] [ECCV'18]
- My research has been successfully applied in human-centered AI analytics funded by NSF/NASA:
 - Vision-based workspace injury prevention and rehabilitation: [FG'18] [JOB'18] [THMS'18 review]
 - Detecting Early Stages of Cognitive Fatigue: [ACCV'10 oral] [TIP'12] [CVPRW'16]
 - Computational American sign language analysis: [ICCV'15] [ICPR'16 oral] [FG'16]

EDUCATION

Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey, New Brunswick, New Jersey, USA

■ Ph.D. in Computer Science

- Sep 2012 Oct 2017
- Thesis: Learning Disentangled Representations in Deep Visual Understanding
- Adviser: Prof. Dimitris N Metaxas

Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Science, Beijing, China

■ M.S. in Computer Science

- Sep 2008 Jul 2011
- Thesis: Multi-scale Visual Object Tracking (Outstanding Master Dissertation)
- Adviser: Prof. Ming Tang

Beihang University, Beijing, China

■ B.S. in Automation Science

Sep 2004 – Jul 2008

EXPERIENCE

Binghamton University - State University of New York, Binghamton, New York, USA

Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Science

Sep 2018 – Now

Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey, New Brunswick, New Jersey, USA

Visiting Professor, Department of Computer Science

Oct 2018 Now

NEC Labs America, Cupertino, California, USA

Research Intern, Media Analytics Group

Jun 2016 – Aug 2016

IBM T. J. Watson Research Center, Yorktown Heights, New York, USA

• Research Intern, Vision Group

Jun 2015 – Dec 2015

Baidu Research, Beijing, China

Software Engineer, NLP Group

Jul 2011 - Jun 2012

PUBLICATIONS

JOURNALS

[1]Rahil Mehrizi, **Xi Peng**, Xu Xu, Shaoting Zhang, Dimitris Metaxas, and Kang Li. A computer vision based method for 3d posture estimation of symmetrical lifting. *Journal of Biomechanics* (**JOB**, *IF*:2.43), 69:40–46, 2018.

- [2]Xi Peng, Rogerio S Feris, Xiaoyu Wang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Red-net: A recurrent encoder-decoder network for video-based face alignment. *International Journal of Computer Vision* (IJCV, IF:11.54), 126(10):1103–1119, 2018.
- [3]**Xi Peng**, Shaoting Zhang, Yang Yu, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Toward personalized modeling: Incremental and ensemble alignment for sequential faces in the wild. *International Journal of Computer Vision* (IJCV, *IF*:11.54), 126(2-4):184–197, 2018.
- [4]**Xi Peng**, Junzhou Huang, Qiong Hu, Shaoting Zhang, Ahmed Elgammal, and Dimitris Metaxas. From circle to 3-sphere: Head pose estimation by instance parameterization. *Computer Vision and Image Understanding* (CVIU, *IF*:2.39), 136:92–102, 2015.
- [5]Ming Tang and **Xi Peng**. Robust tracking with discriminative ranking lists. *IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (TIP, IF:5.07)*, 21(7):3273–3281, 2012.

CONFERENCES

- [6]Zhiqiang Tang, **Xi Peng**, Shijie Geng, Lingfei Wu, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Quantized densely connected u-nets for efficient landmark localization. In *European Conference on Computer Vision* (ECCV), 2018.
- [7]Long Zhao, **Xi Peng**, Mubbasir Kapadia, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Learning to forecast and refine residual motion for image-to-video generation. In *European Conference on Computer Vision* (**ECCV**), 2018.
- [8]Long Zhao, **Xi Peng**, Mubbasir Kapadia, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Learning residual motion in video generation. In *Workshops of European Conference on Computer Vision* (**ECCV Workshops**), 2018.
- [9]Zhiqiang Tang, **Xi Peng**, Shijie Geng, Yizhe Zhu, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Cu-net: Coupled u-nets. In *British Machine Vision Conference* (**BMVC** *Oral*), 2018.
- [10]Yu Tian, **Xi Peng**, Long Zhao, Shaoting Zhang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Cr-gan: Learning complete representations for multi-view generation. In *International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence* (IJCAI), 2018.
- [11]**Xi Peng***, Zhiqiang Tang*, Fei Yang, Rogerio S Feris, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Jointly optimize data and network training: Adversarial data augmentation in human pose estimation. In *Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition* (**CVPR**). * contribute equally, 2018.
- [12]Yizhe Zhu, Mohamed Elhoseiny, Bingchen Liu, **Xi Peng**, and Ahmed Elgammal. A generative adversarial approach for zero-shot learning from noisy texts. In *Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition* (**CVPR**), 2018.
- [13] Rahil Mehrizi, **Xi Peng**, Zhiqiang Tang, Xu Xu, Dimitris Metaxas, and Kang Li. Toward marker-free 3d pose estimation in lifting: A deep multi-view solution. In *IEEE International Conference and Workshops on Automatic Face and Gesture Recognition* (**FG**), 2018.
- [14]**Xi Peng**, Xiang Yu, Kihyuk Sohn, Dimitris N Metaxas, and Manmohan Chandraker. Reconstruction-based disentanglement for pose-invariant face recognition. In *Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2017.
- [15]**Xi Peng**, Rogerio S Feris, Xiaoyu Wang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. A recurrent encoder-decoder network for sequential face alignment. In *European Conference on Computer Vision* (**ECCV** *Oral*, *Best Student Paper Runner-up*), 2016.
- [16]**Xi Peng**, Qiong Hu, Junzhou Huang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Track facial points in unconstrained videos. *British Machine Vision Conference* (**BMVC**), 2016.
- [17]Xi Peng, Nalini Ratha, and Sharathchandra Pankanti. Learning face recognition from limited training data using deep neural networks. In *International Conference on Pattern Recognition* (ICPR Oral, Best Student Paper Runner-up), 2016.
- [18]**Xi Peng**, Junzhou Huang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Sequential face alignment via person-specific modeling in the wild. In *Workshops of Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition* (CVPR Workshops), 2016.
- [19]**Xi Peng**, Shaoting Zhang, Yu Yang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Piefa: Personalized incremental and ensemble face alignment. In *Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV*), 2015.

- [20]**Xi Peng**, Junzhou Huang, Qiong Hu, Shaoting Zhang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Three-dimensional head pose estimation in-the-wild. In *IEEE International Conference and Workshops on Automatic Face and Gesture Recognition* (**FG**), 2015.
- [21]Xi Peng, Junzhou Huang, Qiong Hu, Shaoting Zhang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Head pose estimation by instance parameterization. In *International Conference on Pattern Recognition* (ICPR), 2014.
- [22]Carol Neidle, Jingjing Liu, Bo Liu, **Xi Peng**, Christian Vogler, and Dimitris Metaxas. Computer-based tracking, analysis, and visualization of linguistically significant nonmanual events in american sign language (asl). In *Workshop of Language Resources and Evaluation Conference* (**LREC Workshops**), 2014.
- [23]Qiong Hu, **Xi Peng**, Peng Yang, Fei Yang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Robust multi-pose facial expression recognition. In *International Conference on Pattern Recognition* (**ICPR**), 2014.
- [24]Ming Tang, **Xi Peng**, and Duowen Chen. Robust tracking with discriminative ranking lists. In *Asian Conference on Computer Vision* (**ACCV** *Oral*), 2010.

MANUSCRIPTS UNDER REVIEW

- [25]Xi Peng, Zhiqiang Tang, Yizhe Zhu, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Coconet: Learning a competitive and cooperative agent for network enhancement. *IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI under review)*, 2018.
- [26]Zhiqiang Tang, **Xi Peng**, Kang Li, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Towards efficient u-nets: A coupled and quantized approach. *IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI under review)*, 2018.
- [27]Yu Tian, **Xi Peng**, Long Zhao, Shaoting Zhang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Learning dual-agent for improved inference and generation. In *The Thirty-Third AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence* (**AAAI** *under review*), 2018.
- [28]Rahil Mehrizi, **Xi Peng**, Xu Xu, and Kang Li. A deep neural network-based method for 3d lifting motion estimation. *Journal of Biomechanics* (**JOB** *under review*), 2018.
- [29]Rahil Mehrizi, **Xi Peng**, Xu Xu, Shaoting Zhang, Dimitris Metaxas, and Kang Li. Predicting 3d lower-back joint load in lifting: A deep pose estimation approach. *IEEE Transactions on Human-Machine System* (**THMS** *under review*), 2018.
- [30]Long Zhao, Fangda Han, **Xi Peng**, Xun Zhang, Mubbasir Kapadia, Vladimir Pavlovic, and Dimitris Metaxas. Sketch-based face editing in videos using identity deformation transfer. *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics* (**TVCG** *under review*), 2018.
- [31]Yu Tian, **Xi Peng**, Long Zhao, Shaoting Zhang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Learning complete representations for improved adversarial generation and inference. *International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV in submission)*, 2018.
- [32]Long Zhao, **Xi Peng**, Mubbasir Kapadia, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Learning residual motions in long-term video generation. *International Journal of Computer Vision* (**IJCV** *in submission*), 2018.

PATENTS

- [33]Xiang Yu, Kihyuk Sohn, Manmohan Chandraker, and **Xi Peng**. Siamese reconstruction convolutional neural network for pose-invariant face recognition, 2018. US Patent under process.
- [34]Sharath U Pankanti, **Xi Peng**, and Nalini K Ratha. Visual object recognition, 2017. US Patent App. 15/089,707.
- [35]Ming Tang and **Xi Peng**. A classification-based multi-scale visual object tracking system, 2010. CASIA Software Patent NO. 2010SRBJ6289.

AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS

■ IJCV special issue on Best Paper of ECCV'16	2017
■ ICCV 2017 Doctoral Consortium	2017
■ ECCV 2016 Best Student Paper Runner-up (6 out of 1000+)	2016
■ ICPR 2016 Best Student Paper Runner-up	2016
 Outstanding Graduate Student Fellowship, Rutgers 	2013 - 2014
 Outstanding Graduate Student Fellowship, Rutgers 	2012 – 2013

	■ The 17th Beihang "Fengru Cup" Competition Runner-up (26 out of 600+)	2007
	 Excellent Academic Performance Scholarship (Top 1%), Beihang University 	2006
	 Outstanding Academic Performance Scholarship (Top 5%), Beihang University 	2005, 2007
INVITED TALKS	 "Reduce Data and Human Efforts toward More Efficient AI", at CUNY Graduate C Jun 2018 	Center, NYC, USA
	 "Learning Data Augmentation and Disentanglement for Efficient AI", at Steven Instit NJ, USA 	ute of Technology, May 2018
	• "Reduce Data Efforts for More Efficient AI", at Binghamton University - SUNY , N	Y, USA Apr 2018
	 "Learning Disentangled Representations in Deep Understanding", at MIT-Watson A Feb 2018 	AI Lab, MA, USA
	"Learning Disentangled Representations in Deep Understanding", at IBM Watson NY, USA	Research Center, Jan 2018
	 "Self-supervised Disentanglement Learning via Feature Reconstruction", at IC Consortium, Venice, Italy 	CCV'17 Doctoral Oct 2017
	 "Deep Visual Understanding: Methods and Applications", at Rutgers Thesis I Oct 2017 	Defense, NJ, USA
	 "Learning Face Recognition from Limited Training Data", at ICPR'16 Oral Pres Mexico 	Sentation , Cancun, Dec 2016
	 "A Recurrent Encoder-Decoder Network for Sequential Face Alignment", at Presentation, Amsterdam, Netherlands 	ECCV'16 Oral Oct 2016
	 "Disentangle Subject and Viewpoint by Feature Reconstruction", at NEC Labs A Aug 2016 	merica, CA, USA
	 "Robust Face Verification by Semi-supervised Alignment", IBM Watson Research Aug 2015 	Center, NY, USA,
CO-ADVISED	Rahil Mehrizi, Ph.D. student, co-advised with Prof. Kang Li	Jan 2017 – Now
STUDENTS	 Zhiqiang Tang, Ph.D. student, co-advised with Prof. Dimitris N. Metaxas 	Jan 2017 – Now
	 Yu Tian, Ph.D. student, co-advised with Prof. Dimitris N. Metaxas 	Apr 2017 – Now
	 Long Zhao, Ph.D. student, co-advised with Prof. Dimitris N. Metaxas 	Sep 2017 – Now
TEACHING	■ CS436/CS580L Intro to Machine Learning	Fall 2018
SKILLS	■ Coding: Python, C/C++, OpenCV, OpenGL	
	 Deep Learning: Pytorch, Caffe, Theano 	
	 Systems: Linux, GPU Cluster, Hadoop DFS 	
PROFESSIONAL	Guest Journal Editor:	
ACTIVITES	Neurocomputing (IF:3.32) SI on "Deep feature learning in cross-domain problems."	2018
	Journal Reviewer:	
	■ IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI) IF:9.46	2017, 2018
	■ International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV) IF:11.54	2017, 2018
	■ IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (TIP) IF:5.07	2012, 2016, 2017
	■ IEEE Transactions on Human-Machine System (THMS)	2017, 2018
	■ IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology (TCSVT)	2017
	■ IEEE Access	2017, 2018
	 Neurocomputing 	2016, 2017, 2018
	Pattern Recognition	2016, 2018
	Conference Program Committee:	-
	-	

■ Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)	2019
 Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS) 	2018
 International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 	2018
■ IEEE Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)	2018, 2019
■ IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)	2014, 2016, 2017, 2018
■ European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)	2016, 2018
■ IEEE Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)	2015, 2017
■ Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV)	2018
■ IEEE International Conference on Automatic Face Gesture Recognition (FG)	2018